[wind blowing]
[snippets of Hitler speaking]
[marching Nazis]
[pensive music]
[waves crashing] [wind blowing]
[tense music] [insects chirping]
[typewriter clattering]
[Friederich VO] What is
the true meaning of life?
Pain.
In pain we find truth...
...and in truth - salvation.
[water lapping]
[urgent music]
[retching]
[Margret VO] Dear Mother,
by the time you
receive this letter,
we'll have sold off all
of our worldly possessions
and bought a one-way
ticket to the Galapagos.
[Heinz] Harry?
[Margret VO] Young
Harry's health
has continued to decline,
but we cannot afford the
doctor's recommendation
of two years at a sanatorium,
and Heinz has been inspired
by Friederich Ritter's quest
for a better existence.
[waves crashing]
This is Floreana?
[man] What were you
expecting? Paradise?
Hmm...
[Margret VO] I'm sorry for
leaving without saying goodbye,
but I could not
handle another lecture
about how I married a
man broken by the war.
[Heinz laughing] Finally.
[Margret VO] I'm simply doing
what you always taught me,
supporting my husband.
[waves crashing loudly]
[wondrous music]
[Margret VO] It's true.
This is not the life
I imagined for myself,
but I also never
imagined having to choose
between paying rent and
buying food - no longer.
And remember Harry, Dr. Ritter
has no teeth, so don't stare.
-[Harry] I won't.
-Let's get changed.
The article says it's a
45 minute trek uphill.
[Margret VO] I know you
must think I'm crazy
and perhaps I am,
or perhaps the
world has gone crazy
and escaping it is the
only sane thing to do.
Time will tell.
Yours always, Margret.
[epic orchestral music]
[birds calling]
[Margret] They're
praying. We should go.
Don't be silly.
They're atheists.
Hello!
Excuse me. Hello.
Big smiles now. Harry, you too.
Excuse me.
My name is Heinz Wittmer.
This is my wife, Margret
and my son, Harry.
-You must be Dr. Ritter.
-Hmm...
And you are his
wife, Dore Strauch?
Ah, no.
Are you not Dore?
No, I am, but I'm not his wife.
Marriage makes you sick.
[Friederich] What
brings you to Floreana?
[Heinz] Why - you did.
Your story inspired us to
leave everything behind
and start anew.
Did our story involve
these little safari outfits
and that butterfly net?
[nervous chuckle]
Apologies, the newspaper
said this is how you dress.
What newspapers?
They've been publishing
your letters.
You've been a sensation in
Germany for over a year now.
Did the letters say I
came here to be alone?
[Dore] Ah, I'm drawn
like a hunchback.
-Are there more of these?
-Oh yes. Plenty.
Here...
Come.
Come see my garden.
Thank you.
[Friederich] As we are
strict vegetarians,
this is our main source of food.
Chicken wire keeps
out the feral pigs.
-[Heinz] There are pigs?
-Wild pigs, cows, dogs.
There are many pests.
Many pests.
[Dore] You're a child bride, no?
Excuse me?
Oh, I just, I look at you,
I look at your little son.
I do the math.
Oh, Harry is not my son.
His mother passed away.
I'm Heinz's second wife.
Oh...
You want to come say hello?
[Friederich] Christ!
They are all so shallow.
They are a bit sensational but,
they capture the magic
of your life here.
Nothing about our
life here is magic.
Do you know how long it
took me to clear this brush,
and build, garden?
12 months. Then there's
the issue of water.
What issue?
There is none, no lakes,
no rivers, nothing.
No, just two tiny springs
that collect the rain.
Do not be fooled by our
success, Herr Wittmer.
No one else has been
able to survive,
because life here is
gruesome - frustrating.
Failure is inevitable.
Oh, did you bring food
in that haversack?
[Margret gasping]
[Dore] No, no, no. Don't!
Do not startle that.
That's a Goliath. Its
sting can kill you.
Everything on this
island can kill you.
Well, we didn't come
here to relax, did we?
Why did you come, exactly?
My son had tuberculosis.
His doctor prescribed
a sanatorium,
but given the sordid
state of Germany,
even a man like me with
a good government job
couldn't afford it.
Friederich hates that I
pay him so much attention.
Why?
He says to love an animal
is to indulge in our
petty human desire
for constant affection.
Burro...
[Friederich] How bad
is it, in Germany?
-[Heinz] It's disgusting.
-No, it's inevitable.
Well, I don't know.
Everyone loves to fight for
freedom, then we get lazy.
Democracy leads to
fascism, leads to war.
Democracy, fascism,
war - repeat.
[Dore] And our chickens...
Is it true Frau
Strauch has been healed
of her multiple sclerosis?
-She will be.
-That's wonderful.
May I ask how?
You and the rest of
the world will find out
when I finish my manuscript.
Dore!
Lend the Wittmers your ass.
[grand orchestral music]
Here we are.
You can sleep in those caves.
Pirates carved
those out years ago.
They'll keep you somewhat dry.
And for water, the
spring is there.
Bring the donkey back tonight
or Dore will have your head.
[pensive music]
That is our water source?
[softly chuckling]
[Dore] I don't like them.
She's a simple hausfrau,
he's a naive bureaucrat
and their son, oh my God.
They're going to
need so much help.
We came here for isolation
and now we're being
crowded by this family.
It's not fair on humanity,
who's depending upon
you finishing this work.
What does Nietzsche say, hmm?
There is chaos in a...
Do I advise you to
love thy neighbor?
-No.
Escape thy neighbor.
I settled them in the caves.
Oh my...
It's impossible to
garden up there.
Yeah, you're a genius.
[Friederich] They'll be
gone before the rains end.
[exaggerated insect and
animal noises growing louder]
[Margret moaning]
[coughing]
[mosquitos buzzing]
I hate this place.
[insects buzzing]
[Heinz growling]
[moaning]
[coughing]
[Heinz] Breathe! Breathe!
Come on!
[Margret gasping]
[Heinz muttering] Stop!
Climb it. Climb it.
[gasping]
Same dream?
[animal sounds in distance]
Heinz, I'm late.
It's been three cycles
now and I'm late.
Are you sure?
[gentle laughter]
Congratulations, my love.
[animals fighting]
[dog barking]
[Heinz] Out! Go!
[wild dogs growling]
[Heinz] Out!
It's going to be all right.
[breathing heavily]
[typewriter clattering]
[Friederich VO] For
most of human history,
we have tricked
ourselves into believing
a better world exists
just beyond our grasp.
Christians call it Heaven.
Hindus call it Nirvana.
Muslims call it Paradise.
I call it a lie.
God is dead. There is only man.
Hello!
Hello, Doctor Ritter.
[Friederich VO] If we
want a better world,
we need to fix it in...
I'm sorry to bother,
but I was wondering if I
could borrow your Burro.
We need to bring the
rest of the supplies up.
The wild dogs got into our food.
Sorry, Burro's occupied.
[Friederich VO] We need to
fix the world in this life,
not wait for the next.
How is your writing, Dr. Ritter?
Flowing out of me like a river.
Happy to hear.
They're clearly suffering.
Shall we fuck?
-[Friederich] Your bad leg?
-[Dore] Yeah. It's fine.
Okay, good.
Ahh... Ahh...
[Friederich] Control
the breath. Concentrate.
Ahh...
Ahh... No Dore, eyes closed.
I know.
[Friederich] To the
mind that is still...
[Dore] To the mind
that is still...
[Friederich] The whole
universe surrenders...
[Dore] The whole
I am surrendered to you...
-Ahh...
Hmm...
-Sorry. Sorry.
-Stop, Dore.
-No, watch out?
-What?
-My tooth.
-It's infected.
-It's fine.
-Dore, look at me.
-Look.
-I'm looking at you.
Breathe. Breathe.
[both breathing deeply]
[loud explosion]
[canon exploding]
Idiots.
[knocking on door]
[man] Senorita, the
landing craft is ready,
and everything on the beach
is just as you requested.
I'm coming!
[melancholy music]
I am the embodiment
of perfection.
["Entry of the Gods into
Valhalla" by Wagner playing]
[waves crashing]
[music crescendos]
Gentlemen...
I present, Hacienda Paradiso!
This is where we'll build.
-[birds calling]
-Hmm...
It's perfect, my love.
[softly sighing]
I just can't believe
I actually did it.
We did it!
We are here.
We're pirates.
[chuckling] We're pirates!
[Robert] Come on!
[all whooing]
[Rudy] Hacienda Paradiso!
[all shouting with joy]
[screaming and
laughing with joy]
[dogs barking]
[Manuel] Shoo! Shoo! Shoo! Shoo!
[shouting in Spanish]
[grand orchestral
music] [waves crashing]
[kissing]
Brilliant! Brilliant!
[typewriter clattering]
[rooster crowing]
[Burro braying]
Okay, they're here.
What are we going to do?
[regal music]
[soft chuckle]
Baroness Eloise Wehrborn
de Wagner-Bousquet.
Dore Strauch.
-Baroness.
-Thank you, my love.
Now, where is the
infamous doctor?
I am Ritter.
[Baroness exhaling]
The newspapers did
you no justice?
[gentle laughter]
I've waited a long time to
be in the presence of the man
who tamed nature
and built a kingdom.
It's a simple home.
[chuckling] Oh no...
This place means so much
to your loyal followers.
Everywhere I go -
Vienna, London, Paris.
Presidents, prime ministers,
philosophers in salons -
everyone is talking
about the brilliant man
who extracted his own
teeth to avoid infection
and the woman with
the ironclad will.
Friederich plus Dore -
the sun and his moon -
coming together to build
a future of civilization.
It's a testament to love,
and everyone needs
a great love story.
They're discussing me in salons?
Mais oui.
Are they discussing
how modern civilization
is on the precipice
of self-destruction?
Hmm.
-That's what you believe?
-[Friederich] Of course!
From the ashes of the
destruction will rise
a true democracy no
longer defined by money,
but by the mind.
By the mind...
But darling you can't
throw a good dinner party
with just your mind.
[laughing]
[Friederich chuckling]
Where are you setting up camp?
On the beach, of course.
No, no! No fresh
water on the beach.
I'll show you the
nearest spring.
[laughing and guitar playing]
[Margret] Excuse me!
Hello. Excuse me.
Back off!
I, I, I, live up there with
my family and you are, you are
swimming in our only
source of drinking water.
The hell is going on here?
Rudy, it's fine.
It's okay.
My sincere apologies.
I was in a desperate need
to get the salt off my body.
Baroness Eloise Wehrborn
de Wagner-Bousquet.
We are the Wittmers.
Heinz - Margret.
To what do we owe this... honor?
I'm your new neighbor.
Ah, thank you, darling.
Not all the way up here of
course - what a long walk.
No, I'm building my
hacienda down the beach.
But Rudy, my engineer
- say hi, Rudy.
Rudy says it will take some time
to dig a proper water well,
and Robert, my
bodyguard, agrees.
So in the meantime,
we must borrow yours.
You don't mind, do you?
I brought mail. Some
must be for you.
The rest for Dr. Ritter.
Can you give it to him?
Splendid.
[Baroness] Toodles!
Heinz?
[Friederich] What is this?
These have been opened.
Dore, the mail has been opened.
[Heinz] Not by me.
-Did that woman give you these?
-Oh, you met her.
She came here yesterday,
right after her arrival.
Then why didn't she deliver
the mail to you herself?
Because she wants us to think
that you invaded our privacy.
I underestimated her.
But you welcomed her.
I offered her water.
We were nothing but gracious.
You fought in the war, hmm?
-Verdun.
-The trenches.
Infantry.
You saw a lot.
Humanity at its worst.
Humanity at its truest.
[Baroness] No Rudy, if we
want to attract investors,
we need 14 rooms, not 12.
All ocean facing,
no compromises.
I want a private deck, hammock,
and an ice box for champagne.
Ice requires refrigeration but,
but anything's
possible, my love.
[Heinz] Baroness!
Herr Wittmer, with
a pleasant surprise.
Can I have a word please?
In private.
Of course.
[dog growling and barking]
Marquis. Down! Down! Good boy.
Is this dog wild?
He was, but now
he's a sweetheart.
You can have my lunch.
I've named him Marquis de Sade.
Marquis - Heinz.
How can I help
you, Herr Wittmer?
I came to say,
I do not appreciate you trying
to pit my neighbor against me.
You defiled Dr. Ritter's letters
to make him believe I did it.
Why?
Ah...
Why do you think Dr. Ritter
showed me the way to
your drinking spring
instead of offering his own?
Yes, he's trying to pit
you against me as well.
To get us off this island.
Trust me, by this time next
year, one of us will be gone.
I personally hope it's not you.
Heinz, let me show
you something.
My grand plans are front
page news in Ecuador.
[Heinz] You, you want
to build a hotel here?
Not just any hotel.
The most exclusive
resort in the world.
Millionaires only.
Here?
I shall call it
Hacienda Paradiso.
We are currently in
the honeymoon suite.
Here!?
Yes, here!
Why do you keep asking the
same question over and over?
I no longer have patience for
men who question my ambition.
[unsettling music]
[typewriter clattering]
[Baroness] Good morning, Doctor.
Pig.
What did you say?
I said, good morning,
Doctor - and pig.
How dare you. Say it
again, to my face.
Say it to my face. Come on!
-Say it to my face.
-[Baroness] Huh?
Here I am. Say it to me now.
Pig, pig, pig, pig, pig!
[boar grunting]
Pig! Oh Christ. Dore, a pig.
[Friederich screaming]
-[mooing]
-[Heinz screaming]
-[boar grunting]
-[Friederich] Out! Out!
[Friederich] The vegetables!
[screaming] Out, out, out!
-[Heinz] Margret!
-[cow mooing]
Move the pipe!
Get out of the way.
[Friederich] Bloody pig,
bloody pig! Get out!
[cow mooing]
-[screaming]
-[boar squealing]
We have milk.
God damn!
Would you look at that?
Dr. Ritter doesn't have a gun.
[foreboding music]
[groaning]
[dog barking]
[Margret] Heinz!
What?
Look.
Our first vegetables.
[softly chuckling]
[Baroness] Surprise!
Now we are actual neighbors.
Let me.
[Rudy] Manuel, can you
fill up the canteens?
So much cooler up here.
[Rudy] Yeah...
[Baroness] Tell your
husband not to worry.
This is just until my Hacienda
is built on the beach.
My engineer Rudy is
having a hell of a time
trying to find a working well,
and I am losing my patience.
-Right, Rudy?
-Yeah.
Why did you marry him?
You are so young and innocent.
He's... like a boiled turnip.
There are only two reasons
why you marry an older man.
Either he's rich or you know,
he's gifted.
Oh, so he's gifted. Well done.
I did not say that.
You'd didn't have to...
Baroness please, this is
highly inappropriate...
-It's girl talk.
-Stop it.
You want to hear about
Robert's special gift?
I married him because he asked.
Oh you poor thing.
I don't need your
pity. I need peace.
Come here. Let me hug you.
I'm pregnant.
You're having a baby?
Here?
Yes.
Which means I need
rest, and quiet.
[chuckling] And community.
Lucky for you hospitality
is our specialty.
It's settled.
We're having a baby.
-Well, congratulations.
-We're having a baby.
[Robert] I love babies.
[music playing]
[people chattering]
[tense music rising]
[Burro braying]
[Friederich] Dore!
The boar came back.
[Friederich VO] As
we rebuild society
in the wake of its destruction,
there will be setbacks.
Do not give in.
Because a desperate
man is a pathetic man.
A desperate man is unable
to reason, unable to think,
unable to...
Shit!
[mooing]
[gunshot]
Christ!
They did it.
Good day, Wittmers.
Fine job.
[Heinz] What a nice surprise.
Apologies - this must
be disturbing for you.
Can I have that cow's head?
I'll trade you -
for these chicks.
Well...
Doctor, sorry to bother, but
I was wondering if you
would do me the great honor
of delivering the baby.
I'm afraid not.
-[Heinz] Please.
-[Friederich] I said no.
Shall we get on with this?
Perhaps you would reconsider.
What is the purpose of life?
Excuse me.
You're having a child. There
must be some reason for it.
-Yes.
-Because we want one.
Why?
Because family is
everything to us.
Why?
Because it is.
Because you say it is.
No, because the
world says it is.
Oh, the world.
You're still part of the herd.
You are a sheep, who doesn't
realize that the world
and its universal values
are a pile of shit.
I'm no longer part of that world
and I'm no longer a doctor.
Take it.
Babies are born every day.
Three out of five
chance you'll be fine.
Are we no longer vegetarians?
To be a vegetarian Dore,
one needs vegetables to eat,
which one must garden.
You're too busy playing
arts and crafts.
We have eggs and there's
still fruit on the trees.
We're giving into
the will to live.
Don't throw Schopenhauer at me.
'Will to live'.
-Yes, I want to live.
-No, it's...
-I want to eat.
You should have
seen their garden.
It's incredible what
they've achieved.
But then again,
Margret is able-bodied.
[Dore] Huh...
I am working to the bone for us.
No, you're making a
stick, a walking stick.
-Yeah.
-You should be meditating.
Multiple sclerosis
will not cure itself.
You should be focusing
on your manuscript.
The world will not cure itself.
Or have you forgotten
why we are here?
[dogs barking and
growling in distance]
[insects chirping]
[foreboding music]
[sexual moans and
groans in the distance]
[music playing from tent]
[dog barking]
Harry, can you fetch
us some firewood?
-But we already have firewood.
-Don't argue.
Do what your mother
says, please.
-Fine.
-[sexual moans continue]
-[Baroness] Yes!
-[Robert] Yes!
[moaning continues]
[sensual screams]
[moaning ceases]
[Baroness] Rudy!
Be a good boy and heat up
some canned beef for me.
Be a good boy, now.
Yeah, woof, woof...
We are out.
Of canned beef?
Of canned everything. Rum too.
How could you let this happen?
You know I only eat
food from the mainland.
[Rudy] We've got no food.
We've no food, no garden,
no hotel and no home.
You fucked us and
then you fucked us.
Bravo to our fearless leader.
Ahh...
[exclaiming and sobbing]
[Harry] Are you, are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine, dear.
You're sad.
Aren't we all?
[Harry] But you're a
Baroness, I thought...
Power - it's nothing
without respect.
It's how I got here.
People will only respect you
once you respect yourself.
So do you?
Respect yourself?
I mean, I'd like to.
Follow me.
Where are you going?
I, I can't run.
Yes you can.
The only difference between
fear and courage is conviction.
Repeat after me. I am the
embodiment of perfection.
I am the embodiment
of perfection.
Say it again, and run!
Run!
I am the embodiment
of perfection.
I'm going to be healthy.
Not going to be -
you are! Say it.
I am healthy.
Keep going.
You are almost
there. Keep going!
[uplifting music]
[Baroness laughing]
Whoa!
I can breathe. I can breathe!
I told you so!
[breathing heavily]
May I can work at your hotel?
Darling, you can
be my maître d'.
I have no idea what that means.
But I accept.
[both laughing]
I could do bird watching trips.
You like birds?
I just love them.
Do you eat the birds
on this island?
Gosh, no.
We have chickens.
[laughing] Of course...
What about canned goods?
Ha...
Where are you going?
Hunting with Papa.
Does your father know
you're joining him?
I feel fine. Promise.
Take the dog.
Lump!
Hey, come on.
Got to get moving, huh.
[dog barking] Come.
[loud gasping]
Patience, little one.
A few more weeks.
-Anything?
-No. Nada.
[gasping in pain]
Ahh...
[Margret] Harry!
Heinz!
Baroness, are you there?
[Robert] Come on.
[Margret] Anyone?
Baroness?
Yeah, what's in there?
Anyone?
Manuel?
Rudy?
[painful groans]
[both exclaiming]
[sobbing]
[loud creak]
[painful groaning]
[mooing]
Heinz!
Heinz?
Heinz, the baby's coming.
[Margret] Harry!
Help me!
[mooing]
Heinz!
[distressed gasps]
[wild dog growling]
[loud barking]
[wailing in pain]
No!
That's all?
This will only last a few weeks.
-You help... help...
-Ahh, Manuel...
-Let's go!
-Stop.
-But she might die.
-You stop!
You're here for me, not her.
You help me.
Understood?
[dogs howling]
[Margret] Get away. Stop!
[barking and growling]
[loud wailing]
[loud screaming]
[gunshot]
[Harry] Lump! Get them.
[Heinz] Go away!
[gunshot]
[Harry screaming]
Oh God!
Margret!
-God!
-Heinz!
[Margret whimpering]
Come on.
Heinz...
Wake up.
I'm sorry...
Wake up!
[baby crying]
Go and get the scissors
and the bandages and twine.
[baby continues crying]
Margret, he woke up.
[exhausted coughing]
[loud panting]
[grinding noises]
[Heinz] Dr. Ritter! Dr. Ritter!
My wife had the
baby but she's sick.
I'm sorry to hear that.
But I told you, I told you,
Floreana's no place
to have a baby.
The baby's fine. It's Margret.
Please.
Please!
Friederich.
How long since the birth?
Ah...
Six hours.
-You don't have tools?
-No, I have no tools.
I told you I didn't come
here to be a doctor.
[door opening]
[Friederich] Margret.
It's Friederich.
[Margret wincing]
Painful, yes?
Hmm, you still
feel contractions?
-Hmm...
-All right.
All right.
The placenta is
stuck in the uterus.
It will have to be
removed immediately.
I need hot water and a spoon.
-Yeah. Here.
-Good.
What?
Why didn't you
stop him, hurt him?
You idiot. Now they will be
best friends because of you.
And you are fired. Vete!
All right, relax.
Ah yes, like this.
Hold her. Margret,
I need you to relax.
I'll try and loosen it.
Now, I'm going to
reach in to the uterus
and extract the placenta.
Hold her, Heinz!
[loud tortured screaming]
[Friederich] Good!
[Heinz whispering]
It's over, Margret.
[Friederich] Now I must clean
up - scrape with a spoon.
[sea lions grunting]
[Margret VO] Dear mother,
I do not know when
you'll receive this,
as there has not been
a boat for months.
But I have some
exciting news to share.
Harry's health
continues to improve.
The fresh air of
Floreana is working,
which is a great relief
to both Heinz and myself.
And I am thrilled to
announce the arrival
of your grandson, baby Rolf.
It seems we are making a go
of it here, in the Galapagos.
Please let the
rest of the family
know this wonderful news.
Your loving daughter, Margret.
[baby coughing]
[mosquito buzzing]
[Baroness] Yoddle-ee-ee-hew!
Ah...
We just came to say
congratulations on your new son
-and a wee present.
-Ja...
[baby gurgling]
That's quite something.
It's what neighbors do.
I am also here to apologize for
the recent misunderstandings
between hotel management
and the locals.
Turns out my Ecuadorian
employee is a thief.
Hmm...
Anyway, he's been banished
from the island. Bye-bye.
He's waiting on the beach
for a fishing boat, so...
Know who else
should be punished?
You! For looking so cute.
May I?
Oh...
You are the luckiest boy in
the world, you know that?
Floreana's first native.
Remember him.
I want to celebrate your
little miracle with a luncheon.
Bring your family. I'll
invite the Ritters.
You'll come, yes?
No!
But she's our neighbor.
I don't care if she's Kaiser-
fucking-Wilhelm-the-Fourth!
She stole our food while
you were having a baby,
alone might I add, and then
if that weren't enough,
had the gall to give us
back our oats as a gift.
But the repercussions could
be worse if we say no.
They're dangerous, Heinz.
It's one lunch. Just one.
["L'Amour Est Un Oiseau
Rebelle" from 'Carmen']
[Baroness singing in French]
[gramophone stopping]
[record resumes playing]
[Baroness continues singing]
[music concludes]
[smattering of applause]
-[Robert] Bravo.
-[Baroness laughing]
Welcome, friends.
Thank you for coming to such
a monumental celebration,
at the future location
of Hacienda Paradiso.
A toast...
...to Rolf...
...to my Hacienda,
and to new beginnings.
-Cheers.
[Baroness] And bon appetit.
That is um, an enormous
amount of food.
I take great pride
in my stockpiles.
Oh, Ritter, those are
beautiful chompers.
[Baroness laughing]
-You eat?
-[Dore] No.
[baby gurgling]
Margret, you must tell
us all about the birth.
Was it fun?
-Fun?
-Hm-mm.
Not exactly.
How is your book coming
along, Dr. Ritter?
You're writing a book?
How I love books! Robert
darling, fetch my favorite.
Oh, ja.
I thought Lorenz
was your darling.
"The Picture of Dorian
Gray" by Oscar Wilde.
I take it everywhere with
me. I love, love, love it.
Imagine having the ability
to stay young forever.
I don't think that is
the author's message.
Ah, your book, Doctor?
It's not a book. It's an
entirely new paradigm.
-[Friedrich] No.
-[Dore] Yeah.
It bridges Eastern
and Western philosophy
and when published will
save humanity from itself.
-So it is a book.
-Is the Holy Bible a book?
-Yes.
-No.
Would you please pass
me the stolen meat?
Margret, why did you
marry such a bore?
Oh right, because he asked.
I look forward to reading your
book when it's done, Doctor.
I'm looking forward
to finishing it,
without this
constant interruption
from a stream of tourists.
[Baroness] No
tourists yet, darling.
But they are coming and when
they do, I need workers.
Perhaps I could hire you
to be our resident
philosopher, Doctor?
[Friedrich laughing]
Have I somehow offended you?
[laughing] You think
you're above me.
That your intentions are
more noble than mine.
But you and I, we are
the same. We are whores.
When I arrived, Doctor,
you gave my captain
mail to deliver.
Was it addressed
to family, friends?
No, it was addressed to
the editors of The Times,
The Herald and The
Berliner Daily.
Now, why oh why
would you do that?
He is seeking
recognition and so am I,
by building the world's
most exclusive hotel.
Looks like that's
progressing very well.
[tense music building]
How are you, Dore?
Personally?
Never been better, thank you.
How is your prized Burro?
He's like a child to you, yes?
Makes sense,
given you don't have
any real children.
[Baroness] Me, I've
never wanted kids.
No, they're filthy.
Except for our dear Harry
and Rolf, of course.
Do you Dore, want kids?
We have no interest.
You have no interest.
Dore, on the other hand...
Next subject!
[Baroness] What's the
matter? You haven't tried?
Oh, you have tried.
Ritter's sterile!
Don't be ridiculous.
[Baroness] It would
explain a lot.
-She had a hysterectomy!
-[Dore gasping]
The doctor was a quack.
-Why'd you say that?
-What?
-Doesn't matter.
-Don't say that.
-It's just...
[Dore] This is
nonsense, actually.
Absolute nonsense. All of it.
This lunch, this hotel -
all of it. I'm leaving.
-Oh, Dore.
-You're a fraud.
Sit down. Sit down!
Marquis! Rapport!
[dog growling and barking]
[Friedrich] What are you doing?
-[Heinz] What is this?
-Stop it. Shut up!
I trained him.
[barking]
Viens.
[Baroness] Good.
[Baroness] Dogs are like men.
First, you must hurt them,
then nurse them back to health,
et voila, they love you forever.
I want you off of my island.
If you don't go by
your own free will,
I will personally
throw you in shackles
and drag you off myself!
-Shut up!
-Baroness!
[Baroness] Huh?
As tempting as it
is to be tied up,
I must inform you that
this is not your island.
It is my island.
It's your island, says who?
The Governor of the Galapagos.
Charming man.
It's fake.
-Read it aloud.
-No!
"I hereby grant Baroness Eloise
Wehrborn de Wagner-Bousquet"
"2,500 acres to build
Hacienda Paradiso"
"at the location of her
choosing on Floreana."
Impossible! He granted
me only 40 acres.
Because you lack vision.
Everything you can
see from this beach,
all the way up to your
tiny property is mine.
[Heinz] Let's go.
You have something to say?
[baby quietly gurgling]
Thank you for the lovely meal.
Hmm...
[ominous music]
[Friedrich] I need a rifle.
I'll give you 10 pounds of rice.
You don't hunt.
20 pounds.
[baby gurgling]
Is it true that you just
married me because I asked?
You are letting her
get to your head.
Answer me.
Why are you doing this?
Because it matters.
I was 23, Heinz.
I was still living at home...
...with a younger sister
who was already engaged.
A mother who was constantly
reminding me that I...
...I was too odd, too shy, too
anxious, to ever be a wife.
I had never even been
kissed before I met you.
So yes, I married you
because you asked.
[boar grunting]
[Friedrich] That devil!
Friedrich, don't use that gun.
[boar chewing]
-Friedrich, it's not...
-[loud gunshot]
[boar squealing and then silent]
[birds squawking]
[typewriter clattering]
[Friedrich VO] Do
not run from pain.
Embrace it.
[typewriter clattering]
Pain gives us purpose.
Pain gives us meaning.
Pain tells us we are alive.
[flies buzzing]
Do not be wooed by the
so-called pious among us.
They are false idols
who want to control
us with their morals.
We must block them out.
Likewise, do not be seduced
by the bacchanalian hoards.
Their sole purpose in
life is to distract us.
Their sole purpose is to turn
us back into mindless animals.
No! Their sole purpose is to
destroy us with debauchery,
so we must destroy them first.
[dogs howling]
Because our purpose
is more noble.
No! Because our purpose
is to overcome ourselves.
No! That's Nietzsche.
Our purpose is to
overthrow the system.
Suffering is our goal.
Damn it! Too banal.
Too pedantic.
Our purpose is...
Our, our purpose is...
[discordant music rising]
[Heinz panting softly]
[Heinz] It's all I could find.
[Rudy] Excuse me.
Sorry to bother you.
Can you spare a few mouthfuls?
It's been days for me. Please?
She learned everything
from the movies.
The name 'Baroness',
her continental accent,
the mannerisms, her
stories, it's all fake.
She told me her
mother was a whore
who abandoned her when
she was seven years old.
It's a lie.
She was kicked
out by her parents
because she is a black hole
swallowing everything
in her orbit.
She tore through Europe using
her beauty to curry favor,
only to burn it all down
on her way out the door.
Paris was the only
city she had left,
so she was forced to work
as a cheap Fan Dancer
in the cabarets,
and that's when she
came into my life.
How does Phillipson
fit into this?
Ah, he was an
employee in my shop.
After she spent all my money
and we had nothing left,
she read about Dr. Ritter.
She convinced us
this was our destiny.
-And you believed her?
-[Rudy laughing]
I know. I know I
must sound insane.
But when Eloise loves you...
...it's intoxicating.
Your life suddenly
has divine purpose.
[Baroness] Where the
fuck are my cigarettes?
[Rudy] I told you we've
been out for weeks.
I've been finding your
butt-ends and combining them.
What were you doing up there?
What did you tell them?
What lies are you spreading now?
That's rich.
You were begging. They fed you.
They're trying to divide us.
I don't care, I'm hungry.
I can't control the rains, Rudy.
I'm not a god!
That is the problem.
You are not anything!
[Robert] Hey!
[tense music]
[ship horn blowing]
Deus Ex Machina.
Gentlemen. Welcome to Eden.
[Baroness] Oh my God.
-Clean everything up.
-[Robert] Yeah.
[Baroness] We've been
waiting for this.
[Robert] Yeah, of course.
Rudy, help us clean.
Why?
Because we have a visitor
and he may be your only
ticket off the island.
[film whirring]
-Get the shot?
-Yes, sir.
Great, let's get one
of Post Office Barrel,
then up to Friedo.
I read there's been a
hell of a long drought,
so I brought water, grains,
oils, seeds, canned meats.
["Vous Qui Passez Sans Me
Voir" by Line Renaud playing]
Allan Hancock, pleasure.
Such a short name for the
owner of such a large yacht.
Well, I guess that's
how we do it in America.
I see.
And what exactly do you do
in America, Allan Hancock?
Um...
Well, I'm what you call a
jack of all trades, ma'am.
My, my real passion
is exploration,
but I'm also an oil man, land
developer, and movie director.
You live in Hollywood?
I own Hollywood, ma'am.
You own a house in Hollywood?
Well, I own everything
from the La Brea Tar Pits
to Laurel Canyon.
It's about 10,000
acres, give or take.
Oh, is that the Wittmers?
[wondrous violins]
[group applauding] Bravo.
-Bravo.
-Thank you.
Amazing.
[Allan] Ladies and
gentlemen, I am privileged
to be in such
distinguished company
with the world's top biologists,
botanists, oceanographers,
as well as some of the
bravest folks I know.
Dr. Ritter, you're a pioneer
and we're all looking
forward to reading your work.
Mr. and Mrs. Wittmer, you
achieved the unthinkable,
you had Floreana's first child.
You are the very definition
of survival of the fittest.
Lastly, Baroness...
Now, Dr. Ritter may be
the reason people turned
their attention to this island,
but you, you are the
reason they keep watching.
To those who dare to dream.
[all] To those
who dare to dream.
[man] Bravo.
-Bon appetit, everyone.
-Bon appetit, everybody.
[volcano erupting]
[man] What was that?
[people chattering
and exclaiming]
[Friederich] She's
going to corrupt him.
We must get as much of the food
up to Friedo, as we
can tonight. Come.
Grab what you can.
I'll get all the
rest at first light.
Friederich, stop this.
-Just stop it.
-What?
Stop it.
I know we're hungry, but
this is not who we are.
What, you'd rather they
have it and us to starve?
No, no, I would rather
live by the principles
that you taught me.
What is happening to you?
I want to eat.
I've never seen
you panic before.
[Baroness] Allan, darling,
I have plans to show you.
I can't convince
you to stay longer?
[Allan] Unfortunately, we
have an ocean expedition
planned tomorrow.
Allan!
May I?
I must confess, I had
my doubts about you.
-Really?
-The nouveau riche,
in my experience, are
so unsophisticated.
But you, my dear, you
are a true gentleman.
Um, Baroness, I, I don't think
this is a very good idea.
I'm sorry.
[Baroness] Oh, oh God.
[Baroness exclaiming]
You are all right?
-My chest.
-You okay?
It hurts, it's
tight. [groaning].
Do you feel that?
No, I'll call our doctor.
He can't help.
It's heartache, my dear.
Life is so lonely out here.
There's only one real cure.
[moaning]
[laughing]
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Does this shtick
actually work for you?
Shtick?
Look, we come from
completely different worlds.
No, we don't.
We are both polymaths. We
are both absurdly wealthy.
[chuckling] Eloise,
I love the Baroness,
we all do, but it's an act.
[laughing]
You almost got
me, Allan Hancock.
You dirty man you.
Come kiss me.
[Allan] Goodbye, Eloise.
I have a boat waiting for me.
You will regret this.
I'm quite sure I won't.
[melancholy music]
[Baroness breathing heavily]
[Rudy] Did you ask
him? Will he take me?
He's agreed to
invest in my hotel.
He's very impressed.
-Now help carry the crates up.
-No, I must speak to him now.
-[Robert] Hey, hey, Rudy.
-Who stole my property?
I need to leave. I won't
survive another week here.
Just shut up.
Nobody sleeps until everything
is brought up to my camp.
Ja.
[ominous music]
I am the embodiment
of perfection.
[insects chirping]
I am the embodiment
of perfection.
Come, come.
[dog barking]
Time to choose sides.
[Baroness] How can I
help you, Dr. Ritter?
Tell your boy to fuck off.
Oh, he's protecting
his property.
-My property!
-Our property.
[laughing] Heinz,
you really thought
he was going to share?
How cute.
No, he was going to steal it.
-Don't listen to her bullshit.
-So we would be
starved off the island, see...
[Friederich] Don't
listen to this bullshit.
I'm the only one
looking out for us here.
-We want what is ours...
-Hey!
[Friederich] And then
we're going to leave.
-You put it down.
-Put your weapon down!
Stop pointing that
at her, you hear me?
[Friederich] I want my property.
-Papa!
-[Margret] Harry!
[Harry] Stop now!
What are you doing?
We are neighbors!
Stop this nonsense,
all of you, please.
Where have you been?
[tense music]
[metal clanging]
[gun firing]
[donkey lowing]
I will not let you destroy us.
I'm going hunting.
What, you're going to leave
nothing for my chickens?
Give them this.
-No, this is bad.
-It's pickled!
-I'm not giving this to them.
-They'll be fine.
I'm not wasting good meat
on the fucking chickens.
Eat.
[door knocking]
[Baroness] Rudy?
Rudy, just come out
for a moment please.
This is abuse.
[Baroness] I just want to talk.
Don't be a fool.
Too late for that.
I will never forget the
way you made me feel
when we met.
You made me believe
I had something important
to offer this world.
Take it.
[Rudy] What is this?
Clothing and food.
You are free to go, if
that's what you want.
Never meant to hold
you back, Rudy.
Is there anything
you need before I go?
Hmm.
[dog barking]
[mooing]
[Heinz] What is it?
Hey, hey, calm down.
There's something in the garden.
[Harry] Is it a boar?
[animals lowing]
Hello?
[Heinz] Shit, our water.
[rifle firing] [animal groaning]
[animal exhaling
and falling silent]
Oh, oh no.
[Dore] Friederich?
Friederich, come
and look at this.
I told you not to feed
them spoiled meat.
Come over here!
Burro?
[ominous music]
Where's Burro?
Burro!
[Dore] Margret!
Have you seen him?
Have you seen Burro?
Do you have him?
No, what?
Someone's taken him.
I will kill whoever did this
with my bare fucking hands.
[Margret] Harry, go help her.
[Dore whispering] Someone's
killed him. He's dead.
-[Heinz] Ritter!
-[Dore] I know he's dead.
She had a fall.
Christ!
Dore!
There.
-I did it.
-Idiot!
It was dark.
I didn't... Stop it.
[ominous music]
You were right, it's
time to choose sides.
Eloise?
Dore is broken.
I mean, Heinz practically
carried her home.
[Dore] And Ritter
suspects Heinz?
They're at each other's throats.
You did it.
I don't know how, but you did.
Oh, you did it.
[kiss smacking]
Please, please, no, no.
Don't hurt me, don't
hurt me. [crying]
She made me.
She made me, she told
me I could go home.
I'm so sorry.
Please, I just want to go home.
[gramophone playing music]
[sexual groaning]
We need to reinforce the
roof before the rains come.
Go down to the valley
to collect some grass.
Now?
Yes, both of you.
It's Rolf's first big adventure.
Let's go, Lump.
Come on.
[gramophone music
continues in distance]
The plan is to talk, yes?
We shall talk.
[gramophone music continues]
[male and female
sensual groans continue]
Baroness!
A word.
[Baroness] Come back later.
It can't wait.
Now!
[men grunting]
Oh!
[men grunting and screaming]
[Robert screaming]
[both grunting]
[blood squelching]
[Robert screaming]
[breathing heavily]
[gramophone music continues]
[Heinz breathing heavily]
Baroness.
[Baroness exhales sharply]
Oh, God.
What a relief.
I've been trying to get
away from him for months.
He was violent,
manipulative, possessive.
He was everything I
ran from in Paris.
Gentlemen, I'd like to
offer you something.
Um, I'd like to offer you...
An equal stake in
Hacienda Paradiso.
One quarter each.
You, you have all more than
proven your worth, your talent,
and your aptitude for survival.
Let's make it official.
I go get a pen.
[gunshot]
[body thuds]
[birds squawking]
[gramophone music ends]
[gramophone needle
squeaking in background]
[inhales, exhales sharply]
[squeaking stops]
[low tense music]
[body thudding]
[water splashing]
[low melancholic music]
I'm not going to tell Dore.
You shouldn't tell Margret.
We'll have to tell
them something.
[low tense music]
[thunder crackling]
[rain pattering]
[Rudy] They're gone!
-They're gone.
-Who's gone?
Eloise told me yesterday
that she and Phillipson
were getting on boat to Tahiti.
Of course I didn't believe her,
but when I woke up this
morning, they were gone.
Who left this letter for me?
You?
It's Robert's handwriting.
So, the Baroness
has left the island?
Yeah. On a boat.
I didn't see a boat.
Nor did I.
Well, she's gone.
I'm selling her things.
[Dore] She left
without her clothing.
She took the nice pieces
and her jewellery.
For someone who prized
her possessions,
she left with very little.
I'll take my food
back, of course,
and I'll purchase the cutlery.
Two rugs and the dining table.
100 sucres.
[scoffs] 500.
[Friederich] 125.
-[Rudy] 400.
-[Friederich] Oh.
-[Friederich] 150.
-[Rudy] 300.
200.
You want me to leave?
I need money to leave.
250. Final offer.
[Friederich] I'll give you 225.
What the hell are you
doing? Do not fool me.
[soft tense music]
[door creaks open]
He's going to frame you.
Who?
Dr. Ritter.
For what?
Murder.
We don't even know
if they're dead.
Shall we start over?
I heard a gunshot, yesterday.
I checked your rifle before bed.
It was still loaded.
I checked the bullets, they
were all accounted for.
So you didn't shoot.
Who else has a gun?
Rudy Lorenz? No.
Dr. Ritter?
It wasn't my intention
to confront her.
It was Phillipson.
-Dr. Ritter...
-Stop.
He's going to write
to the Governor.
The Governor will
come. And then what?
You need to leave me.
And go where?
We have built everything
on this island -
despite them trying their
goddamn best to ruin us.
They haven't.
And they won't.
Because we are a family.
[gun rattling]
I put my letter in the barrel.
Soon a ship will come.
This will all be over.
I'm leaving you.
[Friederich laughing]
I'm not joking.
I know.
You're incapable of humor,
which makes it so funny.
We came here to do
the greatest thing.
But all you do is
waste your days
trying to out-wit
your neighbors.
They ruined my life.
No.
No, Friederich.
You ruined your life.
You betrayed the cause.
-Ow.
-Hurts?
Ow! Don't touch that.
That tooth hurts. Yes?
-Don't touch that.
-We came here to face pain.
Hmm?
From now on, we have
a problem, we fix it.
-We face it.
-This is my pain.
This is my pain to overcome.
This is my pain to bare!
Of all that is written.
What is the quote?
Of all that is
written, my love...
[Dore] Don't quote him.
Only what man has
written in his blood!
-Who said that!?
-Do not quote him.
You're an embarrassment.
Who said that? Who said that?
You're an embarrassment to him.
[Friederich laughing]
You're a traitor.
You're a fucking traitor.
[Friederich grunting]
Fuck you.
You want to do it?
[Dore groans]
[Dore panting]
[low tense music]
[insects chirping]
[footsteps crackling]
Dore!
There you are.
Heinz told me your
chickens are sick.
I thought you could use these.
[chickens clucking]
No.
Friederich says ours
will be fine to eat
so long as he boils them.
For eggs, then.
No. No.
What did Dr. Ritter tell
you about the Baroness?
That he killed her?
Careful.
He's lying to you.
He's a dangerous man, Dore.
Friederich Ritter has
devoted his entire life
to practising non-violence.
Then why did he
trade us for a gun?
Because we were living under
extenuating circumstances.
And what happened to your teeth?
They were infected.
I have antiseptic for
your gums, please.
Are you trying to be my friend?
You are not my friend.
I am not your enemy either.
Dr. Ritter is a very smart man
and I'm sure he's
devised a brilliant plan
to push us off the island.
But then what?
It'll just be you and him.
And the peace of mind we
had before you took it.
It is a common
mistake, you know.
To think that you can boil off
bacteria from spoiled meat.
Yes, the bacteria will die.
But not the poisonous toxins
that have already been
released into the flesh.
[Rudy] Hey!
Hey!
Help! Help!
[water splashing]
Hey!
I'll pay you 50 sucres to take
me back to Isabela Island!
We'll be going
against the current.
No, please.
100 sucres!
I'll run out of gas.
400!
Sold. [water splashing]
Yes. I...
[Friederich sobbing]
[Dore] Oh...
[Friederich laughing]
I've had such a breakthrough.
Man is always put above animal,
by Nietzsche, by Christianity.
But our animal instincts
are our inner truth.
[laughing]
We hunt, we fight,
we fuck, we kill.
That is the purpose of life.
Yeah.
For 10,000 years, we've
run from ourselves.
No more.
Shall we celebrate with chicken?
Fantastic idea. [chuckles]
I'm ravenous.
[chickens clucking]
It feels like a massive
space is opened in my brain,
flooded with fresh ideas.
[Friederich exhales sharply]
I feel evolved.
Reborn.
Oh.
Will you try some?
No.
My gum's still bleeding.
More for me.
Now, our years of sacrifice
have led to this moment.
[birds calling] [tranquil music]
Dore?
It's Friederich. He's very sick.
You have to come.
Can you come?
-Harry.
-Hm.
Go find your father.
[Friedrich groaning in pain]
[loud moaning continues]
What happened?
Food poisoning.
An innocent mistake.
[Friedrich moaning]
[moaning and retching]
Come on, Harry, let's go.
[muttering]
[distressed painful moaning]
[Margret] Dore?
I think you should come in.
[moaning continues]
Friedrich...
Now, now you are immortal.
You see?
I curse you...
...with my dying breath.
[Friedrich exhales]
[gentle music]
[birds chirping]
[low tense music]
[sea lions growling]
[man] Attention! Stand
for the Governor.
[Governor] In the house, alone.
[Governor] Why do you
waste my time? Admit it!
[Heinz] I'm not signing.
I will never sign it.
[Governor] Señor Wittmer.
I know what you did.
[calls officer] The wife!
[low tense music]
Your husband killed
the Baroness.
Did he now?
And who told you that?
Dr. Ritter!
[Governor] He wrote a letter.
A fisherman delivered
it last week.
And you believe this nonsense?
Dore Strauch confirmed it.
[baby quietly gurgling]
Do you ever stop and consider
why Dr. Ritter is now dead?
Food poisoning.
A man who has survived
here for four years
suddenly makes the amateur
mistake of eating bad chicken?
Did Dore tell you that I
gave her fresh chicken,
the day before?
Look at the facts, Governor.
Dr. Ritter is now dead.
Rudy Lorenz sold the
Baroness's things and escaped.
Dore is a mess.
But we Wittmers, who have
no quarrels with anyone,
have not run, haven't
done anything suspicious,
are the prime suspects.
[baby gurgling]
Excuse me, gentlemen.
[gentle uplifting music]
[people chattering]
[Governor] You're
the last ones left.
You sure you don't want to go?
This is home.
[gentle uplifting music rising]
[officer] Vamonos.
[gentle piano music]
[gentle orchestral music]